Fencing is a science. Loving is a passion. Duelling is an obsession.
The Duellists is a drama, war film directed by Ridley Scott.
In 1800, as Napoleon Bonaparte rises to power in France, a rivalry erupts between Armand
and Gabriel, two lieutenants in the French Army, over a perceived insult.
For over a decade, they engage in a series of duels amidst larger conflicts, including the failed French
invasion of Russia in 1812, and shifts in the political and social systems of Europe.
Armand d'Hubert, played by Keith Carradine.
Gabriel Feraud, played by Harvey Keitel.
Joseph Fouché, played by Albert Finney.
Colonel Perteley, played by Edward Fox.
Adèle, played by Cristina Raines.
Brigadier-General Treillard, played by Robert Stephens.
The Duellists is a 1977 British historical drama film which
is the directorial debut of Ridley Scott.
Set in France during the Napoleonic Wars, the film focuses on a series of duels between two rival officers, the obsessive Bonapartist Gabriel Feraud (played by
Harvey Keitel) and royalist Armand d'Hubert (Keith Carradine), that spans nearly 20 years and reflects the political tumult of early 19th-century France.
The film is based on Joseph Conrad's 1908 short story "The Duel".
The Duellists unanimously won the award for Best Debut Film at the 1977
Cannes Film Festival, and was nominated for the Palme d'Or.
The Duellists earned widespread acclaim from critics, who praised Scott's
direction and visuals, and the film's historical authenticity.
The fight choreography, by master swordsman William Hobbs, is considered
one of the most accurate depictions of dueling in cinema.
At the 32nd British Academy Film Awards, the film received
nominations for Best Cinematography and Best Costume Design.
The film explores themes of fencing, cossack, napoleonic
wars, based on short story, pistol duel.
The tone is emotional.